Guide to the Nelson Sullivan Video Collection 1976 - 1989 MSS.357
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Film (Box 19)
  - light at J+Bs, undated; cuid6935 (Film cuid6935, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6935)
    Interior footage of electric light bulbs and kitchenware (dark). Followed by night-time footage of traffic and streetlights filmed from above.
  - DOUG, undated; cuid6936 (Film cuid6936, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6936)
    Exterior out-of-focus footage of people walking in the rain with raincoats and umbrellas. Closeups of a cat's face (Doug).
  - Traffic Be C.P., undated; cuid6937 (Film cuid6937, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6937)
    Interior footage of Nelson Sullivan's apartment with a dog (Blackout) and a cat (Doug). Exterior footage of meatpacking workers. Followed by exterior footage of NYC traffic on a trip to Central Park in a cab and footage of Blackout playing in Central Park. Also includes footage of horse-drawn carriages.
  - wet Douglas, undated; cuid6938 (Film cuid6938, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6938)
    Interior footage of Nelson's cat, Douglas, wet and grooming himself. Includes footage of the window and outside buildings.
  - Bo Walk 2, July 1978; cuid6939 (Film cuid6939, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6939)
    Interior footage of Nelson Sullivan's apartment. Exterior shots from the apartment's windows, showing dogwalkers, streets, cars, walls, and foliage.
  - Park Costumes, undated; cuid6940 (Film cuid6940, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6940)
    Footage of people in costumes at the Bethesda Fountain and Terrace in Central Park, and of others photographing and recording them.
    Housing Annotation
    Q 20-05, INS A4
  - Doug - Christ st., undated; cuid6941 (Film cuid6941, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6941)
    Footage of Douglas sitting in the window. Street footage showing vehicles, buildings, pedestrians, garbage, a newspaper delivery van, The Rastro Importers (383 Bleecker Street), 95 Christopher Street, Frankel Pharmacy, Village Cigars, Riker's, the Christopher Street 1 Train station, and more.
    91384
  - P.O. st. film w/ lion - Good, undated; cuid6942 (Film cuid6942, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6942)
    Footage shot in and around Bryant Park and the New York Public Library, showing pigeon-feeding, the library's lion statues, a man asleep on a bench, park workers dragging a tarp, and more. The film features a lot of movement, and the camera frequently turns sideways.
    J 50-31, INS A 31
  - Chris. St., undated; cuid6943 (Film cuid6943, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6943)
    Footage of the area around Christopher and Greenwich Streets, beginning inside the post office then located at 152 Christopher St., showing St. Veronica's Church, and including a walk around the block, down Washington St. to Barrow St., with views of the World Trade Center.
  - Clinic fade in/out, undated; cuid6944 (Film cuid6944, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6944)
    Daytime footage shot in a room lit by sunlight through venetian blinds. Primarily shows of exteriors of brick buildings and trees through the blinds, but also shows some furnishings in the room, and briefly a woman sitting in a chair.
    9291
  - Apre. demonst. fair - poor, undated; cuid6945 (Film cuid6945, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6945)
    Street footage, including shots of a demonstration in which protesters are waving the flag of the Provisional Revolutionary Government of Southern Vietnam, in front of a movie theater playing "Kiss of Her Flesh" and "Climax Says it All", and of 1500 Broadway when it was under construction.
    INS A 18
  - Christ st. Document, undated; cuid6946 (Film cuid6946, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6946)
    Footage of Christopher Street, including Stonewall Inn, Paws and Claws pet shop, Gay Street, Tor Restaurant, and more.
    91351
  - roof top doc., undated; cuid6947 (Film cuid6947, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6947)
    Footage shot from Nelson's roof of the roof itself and of nearby buildings and other sights.
  - Chains + plants, Doug, nails, undated; cuid6948 (Film cuid6948, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6948)
    Footage shot in Nelson's apartment of a cat (Douglas), Nelson in the mirror, his painted fingernails, and plants hanging from chains.
  - Moving zoom, Good 5 9th window, undated; cuid6949 (Film cuid6949, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6949)
    Footage shot in and around Central Park (including the statue of Jose Marti), and from Nelson's apartment at 5 9th Avenue.
    59633
  - lamp s-m #2, undated; cuid6950 (Film cuid6950, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6950)
    Footage of a swinging lampshade.
  - J+B apt, undated; cuid6951 (Film cuid6951, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6951)
    Blurry footage of a street shot from an upstairs window.
    [difficult to make out: deub / lent / dinb / denli etc]
  - BF, undated; cuid6952 (Film cuid6952, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6952)
    Footage of people at the Bethesda Fountain and Terrace in Central Park.
    [Additional housing annotations/title impossible to read]
  - Unidentified Film #1, circa 1976; cuid6953 (Film cuid6953, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6953)
    Footage of the Cherry Grove section of Fire Island on or around the weekend of the US Bicentennial. Includes many buildings and coastal scenes, and a variety of Bicentennial flags. Also included: Hanlan's Beach Hotel and Club, a poster advertising a performance by Marilyn Sokolow at the Ice Palace, a notice advertising for a room share at The Beach Hotel.
    Original format: Super 8mm film, Duration: 3 min., Color, Silent, 50 ft.
  - Unidentified Film #2, undated; cuid6954 (Film cuid6954, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6954)
    Footage shot on the subway, showing the interior of a train, and steps at 72nd and Broadway, 86th St., and others.
  - Unidentified Film #3, undated; cuid6955 (Film cuid6955, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6955)
    Footage shot on the platform of the Christopher Street subway station, and on a 1 train as it leaves the station. There is a cut during the subway ride, the light level of the film changes, and there is additional footage inside of a subway car as it stops at Penn Station and continues on. Shots focus on people, fixtures, railings, advertisements, and more.
  - Unidentified Film #4, undated; cuid6956 (Film cuid6956, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6956)
    Footage of traffic at night shot from inside of a taxi.
  - Unidentified Film #5, undated; cuid6957 (Film cuid6957, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6957)
    Footage showing Brant Mewborn and Rhonda Granger leaving the Plaza Hotel, and a Central Park carriage driver sitting in his carriage. Images end after 15 seconds, followed by a silent, black screen.
  - Unidentified Film #6, undated; cuid6958 (Film cuid6958, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6958)
    Separated Materials
    Footage shot at night from a car near docks, showing ships and signs for shipping lines, as well as other automotive traffic.
  - Unidentified Film #7, undated; cuid6959 (Film cuid6959, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6959)
    Footage shot outside of Nelson's apartment at 5 9th Avenue, with four visitors, three human and one canine. One woman appears first, carrying a pile of documents and a basketball. Another woman and a man appear, along with a dog. Blackout (Nelson's dog) is also present; the two dogs interact.
  - Unidentified Film #8, undated; cuid6960 (Film cuid6960, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6960)
    Footage of animals in a zoo, including a lion, a baboon, alligators, crocodiles, an otter, goats, deer, and more.
  - Unidentified Film #9, undated; cuid6961 (Film cuid6961, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6961)
    Footage shot on the streets of New York's Upper East Side; pedestrians, businesses, and vehicles. The camera is often shaky and out of focus.
  - Unidentified Film #10, undated; cuid6962 (Film cuid6962, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6962)
    Footage shot in Nelson's apartment: a self-portrait in a mirror in the nude, views out the windows, polished fingernails, a cat (Douglas), and the kitchen. The second half of the film depicts Nelson cooking Brown 'n' Serve sausages in a frying pan.
  - Unidentified Film #11 [Sunshine in New York: 1972], undated; cuid6963 (Film cuid6963, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6963)
    Handwritten titles reading "Sunshine in New York: 1972 | John Nelson Sullivan". The title is shot over and over again, with various zooms, pans, and focus pulls. At one point the camera pulls back to reveal the space in which the title was being filmed.
  - Unidentified Film #12, undated; cuid6964 (Film cuid6964, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6964)
    Footage shot inside of an apartment. A woman plays piano and a man watches television. He drinks from a mug.
  - Unidentified Film #13, undated; cuid6965 (Film cuid6965, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6965)
    Footage shot from the roof of Nelson's building, shows pedestrians, vehicles, neighboring buildings, cyclists, and more. Features aggressive camera movements and zooms.
  - Unidentified Film #14, undated; cuid6966 (Film cuid6966, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6966)
    Film begins with footage shot in darkness, showing a lit light bulb, a raging fire, and the lights of emergency vehicles. Second half is daylight footage shot in Nelson's apartment, showing interiors, and shots from the window of pedestrians, men urinating on a wall, foliage, and neighboring buildings. There is a brief shot of Blackout lounging on the floor.
  - Unidentified Film #15, undated; cuid6967 (Film cuid6967, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6967)
    Footage of people at the Bethesda Fountain and Terrace in Central Park, many in costumes. See cuid6940.
  - Unidentified Film #16, undated; cuid6968 (Film cuid6968)
    Original format: Super 8mm film, Duration: 4 min.; No image, not digitized.
  - Unidentified Film #17, undated; cuid6969 (Film cuid6969, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6969)
    Footage of neon "Food Stop" sign and other signs, shot from a building across the street.
    MS 82484
  - Unidentified Film #18, undated; cuid6970 (Film cuid6970, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6970)
    Footage shot on Nelson's rooftop, featuring neighboring buildings and chimneys, as well as Nelson's boots and film cartridges.
    TS 23572
  - Unidentified Film #19, undated; cuid6971 (Film cuid6971, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6971)
    Film of Washington Square, featuring in-camera editing effects and zooms. Shots show the arch, pedestrians, dogs, and more, and is shot in at least two different frame rates so that portions of the film appear to be in slow motion.
  - Unidentified Film #20, undated; cuid6972 (Film cuid6972, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6972)
    Homemade "The End" title cards.
  - Unidentified Film #21, undated; cuid6974 (Film cuid6974, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6974)
    Film begins with footage shot in South Carolina in or about 1972. Features shots from and of a Porsche 911E, including gas stations on and around East Church Street, of Dodd's store, and of a man in white entering a house. This exterior footage is followed by a title, shot against a TV screen, which reads "FIVE THINGS TO LOOK AT | NELSON SULLIVAN | 1972".
    9290
  - Unidentified Film #22, undated; cuid6975 (Film cuid6975, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6975)
    Footage of people in Central Park at the Bethesda Fountain and Terrace, boating on the Lake, and walking on Bow Bridge and on paths.
    E77-56
  - Unidentified Film #23, undated; cuid6976 (Film cuid6976)
    Original format: Super 8mm film, Duration: 4 min.; Black leader, not digitized.
    13-349
  - Unidentified Film #24, undated; cuid6978 (Film cuid6978, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6978)
    Footage of a cat (Douglas), titles reading "FIVE MOVEMENTS" and "the end," and Nelson in the nude in a mirror.
    14, [barely legible; Germany?] #1
  - pink light, undated; cuid6973 (Film cuid6973, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6973)
    Footage of neon "Food Stop" sign, shot from a building across the street.
  - lamp s-m #1, undated; cuid6977 (Film cuid6977, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6977)
  - Black Velvet, Part 1, 5-1, undated; cuid6979 (Film cuid6979)
    Commercial copy of Brad Chapman's film "Black Velvet, Part 1."
    Original format: 8mm film, Duration: 16 min.; This item was not digitized due to its status as a commercial work.
  - Earon Solo, undated; cuid6980 (Film cuid6980)
    Original format: 8mm film, Duration: 16 min.; This film was not digitized due to its status as a commercial work.
    Commercial copy of a pornographic film.
  - Collage, 1972; cuid6981 (Film cuid6981, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss357_cuid6981)
    Gay pornography / stag film interspliced with title cards and credits of feature films; Title cards include: "Pope Visits - Soft Ver" and many others; A collage of various film segments, title cards, head leaders, tens of very short segments, including films such as Lawrence of Arabia, but alos gay pornography scenes and intertitles.
    Original format: 8mm film, Duration: 16 min.
  - VB-3 Bayside, undated; cuid6982 (Film cuid6982)
    Commercial copy of Target Studios's film "Bayside."
    Original format: Super 8mm film, Duration: 16 min.; This item was not digitized due to its status as a commerical work.
    Copyright Target Studios, Reproduction Forbidden Without Written Permission
  - Super 8mm leader, undated; cuid6983 (Box 19)
    Super 8mm leader
  - Super 8mm leader, undated; cuid6984 (Box 19)
  - On Location With Lawrence of Arabia [8mm souvenir film], cuid6985 (Box 19)
    General
    This is a souvenir version of Lawrence of Arabia (1962). Includes insert with ads and an order form.
    On Location With Lawrence of Arabia, Souvenir 8mm home movie, silent edition, in color. 8mm Columbia Home Pictures. Includes ad for "The finest in home movises from the Hollywood Studios of Columbia Pictures, TV Studios of Screen Gems".
  - Pope Paul VI Visits the Unites States [souvenir filmg, cuid6986 (Box 19)
    This is a souvenir film of the popes visit.
    Pope Paul VI Visits the Unites States. Enjoy this historic event in your home! 8mm b&w silent N-1. 8mm home movies, Republic Pictures.
  - Boss of Rawhide [souvenir film], cuid6987 (Box 19)
    This is a souvenir version of Boss of Rawhide (1943). The original feature has been edited down to 4 min.
    Select Film Library, Official Films, Rootin' Tootin' Shootin' Western. Select Film Westerns. Boss of Rawhide, Dave O'Brien. Includes advertisement for Official Films, distributed exclusively by Select Film Library, New York, NY.
  - Ghost of Hidden Valley [souvenir film], cuid6988 (Box 19)
    This is a souvenir version of Ghost of Hidden Valley (1946). The original feature has been edited down to 4 min.
    Select Film Library, Official Films, Rootin' Tootin' Shootin' Western. Select Film Westerns. 352 - Ghost of Hidden Valley ,Buster Crabbe - Western. Includes advertisement for Official Films, distributed exclusively by Select Film Library, New York, NY.
  - Return of the Rangers, cuid6989 (Box 19)
    This is a souvenir version of Return of the Rangers (1943). The original feature has been edited down to 4 min.
    Select Film Library, Official Films, Rootin' Tootin' Shootin' Western. Select Film Westerns. 353 - Return of the Rangers, Tex O'Brien - Western. Includes advertisement for Official Films, distributed exclusively by Select Film Library, New York, NY.
  - The Return of Dracula [souvenir film], cuid6990 (Box 19)
    This is a souvenir version of Return of Dracula (1958). The original feature has been edited down to 4 min.
    Standard 8mm, the Return of Dracula, SpookyHooky Thrillers and Chillers
  - The Beast with 5 Fingers, cuid6991 (Box 19)
    This is a souvenir version of The Beast with 5 Fingers (1946). The original feature has been edited down to 4 min.
    Standard 8mm, the Beast With 5 Fingers. SpookyHooky Thrillers and Chillers
  - Empty film box, cuid6992 (Box 19)
    Pennsylvania -cocktails after Dove shoot, 10. Chrome Movie Film. 31091, 903.
  - Annotated Film Containers, 1975-1990 (Box 19)
    Original film containers that held 8mm and Super8mm films shot by Nelson Sullivan (see cuids 6924-6982). Handwritten annotations are found on many of the containers.
    The films have been digitized, rehoused, and stored separately for conservation reasons. See cuid6924-cuid6982 for details about the content.
- Series III: Photographic Material
  - Subseries A: Slides
    Slides include:
    Building of Pyramids on the Beach of F.I.: Kodachrome 64; Eddie and Freddy, Fire Island, Pyramid Scenes: Kodachrome 64, 20 exps.; Fire Island, Eddie and Freddy: Kodachrome 64; Fire Island, Nelson Haircutting Seen: Kodachrome 25; From Roof at 5 9th Ave; Good Ice Palace, Inside and Out; July 4th 1976 Cherry Grove; Masako and Her Baby, Chelsea Street, Fire Island and Nelson: some good double exposure, Kodachrome 64; Untitled
    - Nelson's Slides 1975-77, 1975-1977 (Binder A)
  - Subseries B: Photographic Prints
    - Paula Gately Tillman Portrait of Nelson Sullivan, 1986 (Binder A)
      Provenance
      This item was donated to the Fales Library by Paula Gately Tillman, July 2014.
    - Artist Statement by Paula Gately Tillman, 2003 (Binder A)
      This document accompanied the Paula Gately Tillman Portrait of Nelson Sullivan, donated to Fales Library in July 2014.